Contact

neilkester@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/neilkester (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Military

Command

Leadership

Certifications

Project Management Professional

Honors-Awards

MORS Wayne P. Hughes Junior Analyst of the Year

AORS Junior Analyst of the Year

Dr. Christian J. Lambertsen Award for Operational Innovation

Publications

DEVS Distributed Modeling Framework - A Parallel DEVS Implementation via Microservices

Neil Kester

Operations Research Analyst

Greater Tampa Bay Area

Summary

A proven leader of both tactical and analytic teams confronted with challenging environments and problem sets. Dedicated to building, mentoring, and inspiring teams to grow professionally and personally into agile problem solvers. An experienced operations researcher skilled in the application of data science techniques and traditional analytic methods. Excels at achieving desired effects with minimal guidance and oversight in environments that demand the insight and innovation of a self-motivated leader.

Experience

US Army
Military Analyst
July 2019 - Present (3 years)
Tampa/St. Petersburg, Florida Area

U.S. Army Center for Army Analysis Military Analyst August 2016 - June 2019 (2 years 11 months) Washington D.C. Metro Area

US Army Materiel Systems Analysis Activity (AMSAA) Military Analyst June 2014 - May 2016 (2 years) Aberdeen, MD

AMSAA is the Army's premier provider of performance data and analysis at the system and component level across the entire materiel life cycle. I conducted analysis of item level performance through the use of computer and mathematical simulations, statistical testing, and data visualization using tools such as R, @Risk, and Excel. I developed extensive knowledge of powerful R packages such as ggplot2, dplyr, Shiny, and RMarkdown to create scripts which automatically aggregated and cleaned model output data and then visualized the data in an interactive format using R Shiny.

US Army Corps of Engineers
1 year 9 months

i year 9 monus

Project Manager October 2013 - June 2014 (9 months)

Seattle, WA

The USACE Project Manager manages scope, schedule, quality, and budget while leading the project delivery team to successful project execution. Serves as the primary interface with the customer and is the US Army Corp of Engineers' primary internal advocate for the project. I managed several medium and small projects that varied in scope from construction project design to institutional process development and implementation.

Project Engineer

October 2012 - October 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Joint Base Lewish McChord, WA

Managed a \$10 Mil construction project through initiating and executing phases. Monitored work for compliance to applicable codes, accepted engineering practices, and schedule. Throughout project execution, identified, coordinated, and integrated customer requirements into project execution.

US Army

2 years 1 month

Company Commander

April 2011 - October 2012 (1 year 7 months)

Afghanistan and Germany

Commanded a Combat Engineer Company deployed in support of combat operations in northern Afghanistan. Responsible for the training, welfare, discipline, and employment of 120 Soldiers organized into four maneuver platoons. Prioritized unit resources including time, equipment, money and facilities to assigned missions that included Counterinsurgency operations spanning more than 180km of international borders between four countries and partnership with the Afghan National and Border Police. Responsible for the maintenance, readiness, and accountability of 41 wheeled vehicles and equipment valued in excess of \$31 mil.

Assistant Battalion Operations Officer (S-3)

October 2010 - April 2011 (7 months)

Baumholder, Germany

Served as the Battalion's long range (Future Operations) planner, coordinating and synchronizing plans and resources with other staff sections and organizations on large scale operations. Specifically focused on pre-

deployment training requirements to deploy the Battalion in support of combat operations.

US Army

2 years 5 months

Battalion Engineer

April 2008 - April 2009 (1 year 1 month)

Conducted contingency contracting support and project management of host nation contractors in support of the Commander's Emergency Relief Program. Coordinated and leveled combat engineer assets across the battalion's battle space to maximize effectiveness of unit resources. Planned, coordinated, and oversaw the execution of the decomposition of combat outposts in the battle space and the redistribution of those resources across the Theater of Operations.

Company Executive Officer

August 2007 - April 2008 (9 months)

Fort Hood, TX

Served as the second in command of a Combat Engineer Company. Primary missions included overseeing the maintenance, readiness, and accountability of 18 tracked vehicles, 11 wheeled vehicles, and equipment valued at over \$20 mil. Supervised company operations and managed training resources and coordination.

Platoon Leader

December 2006 - August 2007 (9 months)

Fort Hood, TX

Responsible for the training, health, welfare, and morale of 30 Soldiers and their families. Responsible for the maintenance and combat readiness of seven tracked and wheeled vehicles valued in excess of \$10 mil.

Education

Johns Hopkins Whiting School of Engineering

Master of Science - MS, Systems Engineering (2017 - 2021)

Udacity

Introduction to Machine Learning with Tensorflow Nanodegree, Artificial Intelligence · (February 2022 - March 2022)

Missouri University of Science and Technology

Master of Science - MS, Engineering/Industrial Management · (2010 - 2010)

United States Military Academy at West Point Bachelor of Science - BS, Civil Engineering · (2002 - 2006)